Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you,
you are watching UD Real, I am
your own personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma. The
Shri of today's video
goes to the comment section. Sir, thank you very much for your question.
You have commented in the comment section of the ICC
Prudential Savings Suraksha Plan
video.
You say that you have a Savings Suraksha Plan of ICC
Prudential Life Insurance Company
Limited, where
you are paying a monthly deposit of Rs 3000,
and the policy term is 10 years,
and you have also taken a premium payment of 10 years, that is,
you will pay the premium continuously for the number of years that are positive,
and you want to know
what benefit you will get, so this comment has made it
clear here. Today we are
understanding the maturity benefit of this plan, according to
their comment. If you also want to understand the maturity benefit of ICC
Prudential Life Insurance Company
Limited's Savings Suraksha Plan,
along with information about the eligibility criteria, then you will already find the video on the channel,
and the part of this video  The link is
given in the description of today's video
and he has commented on this video
and as you all know
that our videos are continuously uploaded as per your suggestions and
questions, so stay
connected with us, like the video,
share it and subscribe to the channel and turn on the
notification bell. Now, to know the
maturity benefit of the plan,
we need some information
like what would have been Aayu's age at the time of purchasing the plan.
He did not tell us, so we are
assuming here that sir, he must have been 30
years old and he must have been a
person in good health when he
purchased this plan. We do not
know anything else, but as per the conditions of the plan, the premium is
10 times the annual basic premium. At the rate of ₹3000, the
annual premium becomes ₹36000. If we multiply it by
10, then it becomes ₹37000.
Understandably, in this plan,
you get a guaranteed addition for the first five years of the policy.
Now, the calculation of the guaranteed addition
is guaranteed.  It happens on maturity
benefit, so as per example the
guaranteed majority benefit is Rs.2 lakh
67633 and its information is
written in the policy band and
in the printed maturity benefit, the plan
says that it depends on when you
take the plan, what is your policy term,
what is the premium payment term, sum
on death how much you have taken,
according to this the guaranteed majority benefit is
decided i.e.
fixed when you take the plan
and the time is told to you and the
guaranteed majority benefit can be
less than the sum on date i.e. your base,
right, in the first five years of the policy
we get a guaranteed addition which will be
calculated on the guaranteed maturity benefit,
so in such a case the guaranteed addition rate
that will be applied will be 5%,
in this plan the guaranteed addition that will accumulate in the first 5 years will be
5% of Rs.2 lakh 67633, now we will withdraw it in the first 5
years  If we multiply 10 by five,
we will get that
we will get Rs. 1338165 every year, which will total to
Rs. 6690.25. What is the cute guaranteed
addition that I have in a year? Now what do I get on maturity? On
maturity, we get
guaranteed majority benefit, which we know,
accurate guaranteed addition, which we have taken out.
Now the topic here is vested
reversal bonus. Now this vested reverse bonus
is a new bonus. You can also call it a simple reversal bonus,
which is available in compound vest. Along with
this, there is a terminal bonus.
So, we have to know two more things here. The
rate of bonus in the last few years, if you
look at the information on their website, it has been
between 0.5 percent to 2.15 percent. So,
we are
assuming a bonus rate of 1.75% here, an average bonus
rate, so that we can calculate an average.
What is the average rate that we are assuming here?
1.75% plainly says that the bonus is of  The
calculation will be done on the guaranteed majority benefit,
so at the end of the first year of the policy, if
you withdraw 1.75% of 2 lakh 67133, then there will be a bonus of 4683 paise
here. Now, this 4683
Ravana Ravana money will be added to 2 lakh 67633.
Why will you add it because
you are getting compound interest here, where you will add
this amount and the
second term of the policy will be added there and the amount that will be added there will be
₹27231658 paise. If you withdraw
1.75% of this, then
this amount of 4765 54 paise will be for the second
term and the bonus. In this way, when
you keep calculating on a compound basis,
then the average wastage simple reversal
bonus will be Rs 50000 47 paise. So,
here I have also come to know the base revisionary bonus.
Now we have to talk about the
terminal bonus here and the rate of terminal bonus.  It is
15%, now we are calculating it
on the Guaranteed Maturity Benefit
because the bonus calculation of Vested Simple Reversal is
also done on this, so
we will get 15.50% of 200000 633,
so
it will be mounted around 41483 16 paise,
okay, you have to check the rest of the bonus rate yourself,
so the link is given in the description of the video,
so
what will be the maturity benefit here, Guaranteed Maturity
Benefit ₹267633 along with that, Across Guarantee
Addition
669825 paise, along with that, Vested Simple
Revolutionary Bonus which is
₹50000-47 paise, along with that, by
saying terminal, you can calculate it around 41000 483 16 paise,
maturity benefit will be
shown here in this manner,
42672583 paise, right, in this manner you can get
maturity benefit  We will calculate the benefit
and if you want to know more about this plan then the
video is already available on the channel, the
link is in the description of the video, you will have to
watch that video because
repeating the same thing spoils your time,
right, so sir, now change your policy,
see in it the guaranteed
maturity benefit,
apply this example accordingly, thank you,
thank you very much to all of you for watching the video till the end, understand one thing yourself and make
others understand that insurance is
not taken without even one protection and
if you found the information of the video clear on the channel, then
please like and share the video,
tell us in the comment section that you
want the next video on this topic, which
plan do you want to know about, do
not take a policy without reading the policy document, right
[Music]